Marcel Thiemann

DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION SPECIALIST | CSPO®

www.linkedin.com/in/marcelthiemann | www.github.com/cestmarcel | www.marcelthiemann.com

SUMMARY

Product specialist and developer with a background in strategic marketing. Collaborative self-starter and problem solver with a strong customer focus and an analytical mindset. Experience with Fortune 500 as well as Small and Medium Companies.

SKILLSET

Professional Skills Agile, Design thinking, Product management, Data analytics, Market research Programming Languages & Engineering Skills JavaScript, MERN-stack, SQL/NoSQL, HTML/CSS Technologies Digital reality, Connectivity platforms, APIs, IoT, Enterprise business technology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Project Lead10/2020-ongoingPATIO Interactive, Inc.Toronto, ON, Canada

- Managing project-based, cross-functional teams of digital consultants, designers, and software developers
- As product owner, supporting the broader team in understanding the client's business challenges & goals

Product Engagement Lead 10/2017-02/2020
Xapix, Inc. San Francisco, CA, USA

- Led go-to-market and product launch for an enterprise software product in the mobility space
- Cross-functional position: Product development, product marketing, and business strategy responsibilities

Digital Strategist09/2013-08/2015Glanzer + PartnerStuttgart, Germany

- Key team member in the company's digital unit. Focused on new business efforts and C-level presentations.
- Planned integrated digital strategies for products and services in the automotive and technology sectors

EDUCATION

Quantic School of Business & Technology 03/2021–ongoing

Master of Business Administration 03/2021–ongoing

Washington, DC, USA

Expected graduation: March 2022

Berlin University of the Arts 10/2015–09/2017

Communication in Social and Economic Contexts, Master of Arts Berlin, Germany

Concentration: Design thinking, technology marketing, political communication

University of Hohenheim 10/2010-09/2013

Communications, Bachelor of Science Stuttgart, Germany

Concentration: Political communication, quantitative research, statistics

CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Alliance valid through 03/2023

Certified Scrum Product Owner Credential ID 1345110

University of Toronto 05/2020-08/2020 Full Stack Coding, Certificate Toronto, ON, Canada

Focus: Software development, computer science basics, frontend & backend technologies